Zoë McDaniel

\$ 804.298.9515 @ zmcdaniel@gmail.com % https://zoemcdaniel.com ♥ Seattle, WA

SUMMARY

I'm a full-stack, front-leaning web developer with a passion for building thoughtful interactions between people and objects. My diverse experiences ranging from code to customer satisfaction to carpentry make me a creative problem solver who continuously strives to improve my skills and knowledge.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer - Freelance

Independent Consultant 2016 - ongoing Seattle, WA

A freelancer and consultant, I provide modern and compelling web design and development services for businesses, individuals, non-profit organizations, and educational institutions in the Seattle region and beyond.

 Collaborated closely with several clients where I specialize in quick adaptation to new codebases, languages technologies

Full Stack Web Developer

General Assembly 2016 - ongoing Seattle, WA

I created and developed scalable products in stacks including Ruby on Rails and MEAN. I bolstered skills in development as well as collaborative teamwork to develop, maintain, and secure web applications

- Built and deployed four project web apps with normalized databases, MVC organization, RESTful routes, & DRY coding concepts
- Planned applications from the ground up, including wireframes, features, code organization, & database tables, prioritizing accordingly to deliver fully functioning projects in less than 5 days

Front of House

Various Restaurants 2013 - 2016 Seattle, WA

As a front of house professional, I mastered every position and was constantly recognized for high sales, customer rapport, repeat visitors, and a hands-on approach to learning the story behind the food. Roles included assistant manager and catering specialist

- Personally hosted high profile guests such as Seahawks' Richard Sherman, Mariners' Robinson Cano, and US National Women's Soccer Team
- Published marketing materials and ran successful promoting campaigns. Designed and wrote weekly newsletter with 20% open/read-through rate. Managed and regularly updated social media and company website
- Outperformed sales expectations with numbers exceeding \$4,000

Full Stack Web Developer

True North LLC 2013 - 2015 Virginia Beach, VA

At this small general contracting company, I was both a historical preservation contractor as well as a web developer

- Developed and managed regularly updated company website and portfolio, eventually migrating it to Wordpress
- Renovated, painted, and restored 18th-19th century buildings and homes

PROJECTS

Mind Dump

A freeform journaling and mindfulness application that provides linguistic tone analysis

- Sole designer and developer
- Leveraged IBM machine learning technology

Accio Bike

Developer, designer, & manager for Ruby on Rails app for prevention & recovery from bicycle theft

- Project manager for team of four
- Completed project in a one-week sprint

Gem Jam

Designed & developed retro-inspired platformer game using the Phaser.io Javascript engine

- Hand-created custom spritesheet
- Completed project in a 5-day sprint

TECHNOLOGIES

Languages

Javascript Python Ruby Java

Web Frameworks



Software



EDUCATION

Computer Science

University of San Francisco 2011 - 2013 San Francisco, CA

Web Development **Immersive**

General Assembly

2016 Seattle, WA